Guide to the Robert Maynard Hutchins Papers 1884-2000
University of Chicago Library
- Series X: Writings
  - Subseries 5: Engagements
    - "The Good News of Damnation" (January 8, 1947), 1947 (Box 413, Folder 37)
    - North Park College (January 14, 1947) -- Slip Only, undated (Box 413, Folder 38)
    - "What Man has Made of his World" (January 21, 1947), 1947 (Box 414, Folder 1)
    - "The Good News of Damnation" (February 19, 1947), 1947 (Box 414, Folder 2)
    - "The Good News of Damnation" (March 4, 1947), 1947 (Box 414, Folder 3)
    - "The Significance of Education (March 4, 1947), 1947 (Box 414, Folder 4)
    - "The Good News of Damnation" (March 6, 1947), 1947 (Box 414, Folder 5)
    - "Is the Educational System Obsolete?" (March 28, 1947), 1947 (Box 414, Folder 6)
    - "Where do we go from Here in Education?" (May 12, 1947), 1947 (Box 414, Folder 7)
    - University of Chicago Alumni Club (May 12, 1947) – Slip Only, undated (Box 414, Folder 8)
    - University of Illinois Symposium (May 16, 1947), 1947 (Box 414, Folder 9)
    - Presbyterian Education Association (June 25, 1947), 1947 (Box 414, Folder 10)
    - Presbyterian Education Association (June 26, 1947), 1947 (Box 414, Folder 11)
    - Presbyterian Education Association (June 27, 1947), 1947 (Box 414, Folder 12)
    - N.A.V.E.D. (August 5, 1947), 1947 (Box 414, Folder 13)
    - "The Possibilities of Moral Education" (September 22, 1947), 1947 (Box 414, Folder 14)
    - "Atomic Energy" (October 3, 1947) -- Slip Only, undated (Box 414, Folder 15)
    - "The Outlook for Education" (October 5, 1947), 1947 (Box 414, Folder 16)
    - "The Constitutional Foundations of World Order" (October 13, 1947), 1947 (Box 414, Folder 17)
    - "Why Businessmen Should be Interested in the Great Books" (October 21, 1947), 1947 (Box 414, Folder 18)
    - Cleveland College (October 22, 1947), 1947 (Box 414, Folder 19)
    - "Education in the Present Crisis" (November 8, 1947), 1947 (Box 414, Folder 20)
    - "On the Education We Need" (November 12, 1947), 1947 (Box 414, Folder 21)
    - "The Constitutional Foundations of World Order" (November 13, 1947), 1947 (Box 414, Folder 22)
    - "The Foundations of World Order" (November 17, 1947), 1947 (Box 414, Folder 23)
    - Kentucky Library Association (November 21, 1947) -- Slip Only, undated (Box 414, Folder 24)
    - Friends of the Kentucky Library Association (November 21, 1947), 1947 (Box 414, Folder 25)
    - Citizens' Board (December 2, 1947), 1947 (Box 414, Folder 26)
    - "Industrial Applications of Atomic Energy" (December 5, 1947), 1947 (Box 414, Folder 27)
    - City Club of Rochester (December 13, 1947) -- Slip Only, undated (Box 414, Folder 28)
    - "Universal Military Training" (December 14, 1947), 1947 (Box 414, Folder 29)
    - American Association of Teachers of Journalism (December 30, 1947), 1947, 1967 (Box 414, Folder 30)
    - Great Books Group (January 15, 1948), 1948 (Box 414, Folder 31)
    - "The Foundations of World Order" (January 21, 1948), 1947-1948 (Box 414, Folder 32)
    - Indiana University (January 28, 1948), 1948 (Box 414, Folder 33)
    - University of Buffalo (February 5, 1948), 1948 (Box 414, Folder 34)
    - Ontario Secondary School Teachers (February 6, 1948) -- Slip Only, undated (Box 414, Folder 35)
    - University of Pennsylvania (February 18, 1948), 1948 (Box 414, Folder 36)
    - National Industrial Conference (February 19, 1948) -- Slip Only, undated (Box 414, Folder 37)
    - Industrial Research Directors (February 20, 1948) -- Slip Only, undated (Box 414, Folder 38)
    - "The Foundations of World Order" (February 26, 1948), 1948 (Box 414, Folder 39)
    - Great Books Discussion Groups (March 2, 1948), 1948 (Box 414, Folder 40)
    - "The Foundations of World Order" (March 14, 1948), 1948 (Box 415, Folder 1)
    - "The Object of Liberal Education" (March 31, 1948), 1947-1948 (Box 415, Folder 2)
    - University of Chicago Round Table (April 4, 1948), 1948 (Box 415, Folder 3)
    - Condon Dinner (April 12, 1948), 1948 (Box 415, Folder 4)
    - Judd Dinner (April 15, 1948), 1948 (Box 415, Folder 5)
    - Des Moines Public Forums (April 20, 1948), 1948 (Box 415, Folder 6)
    - Association of State Universities (May 5, 1948) -- Slip Only, undated (Box 415, Folder 7)
    - Trustees' Dinner (May 12, 1948), 1948 (Box 415, Folder 8)
    - Frankfurt Celebration (May 18, 1948), 1948 (Box 415, Folder 9)
    - "International Intellectual Cooperation" (May 19, 1948), 1948 (Box 415, Folder 10)
    - Iowa Wesleyan Conference (May 31, 1948) -- Slip Only, undated (Box 415, Folder 11)
    - American Civil Liberties Union (June 2, 1948), 1948 (Box 415, Folder 12)
    - Great Books (June 11, 1948) – Slip Only, undated (Box 415, Folder 13)
    - University of Wyoming (June 15, 1948), 1948 (Box 415, Folder 14)
    - School of Medicine Alumni (June 23, 1948) -- Slip Only, undated (Box 415, Folder 15)
    - Institute for Higher Education (July 26-29, 1948) -- Slip Only, undated (Box 415, Folder 16)
    - Encyclopædia Britannica Films (August 2, 1948) -- Slip Only, undated (Box 415, Folder 17)
    - "The Arts of Freedom" (September 21, 1948), 1948 (Box 415, Folder 18)
    - "Higher Education Today" (September 22, 1948), 1948 (Box 415, Folder 19)
    - "Higher Education Today" (September 23, 1948), 1948 (Box 415, Folder 20)
    - FHD (October 1, 1948), 1948 (Box 415, Folder 21)
    - Funeral of Charles H. Swift (October 2, 1948), 1948 (Box 415, Folder 22)
    - "Industry and the Atom" (October 11, 1948), 1948 (Box 415, Folder 23)
    - Cancer Research Foundation (October 15, 1948), 1948 (Box 415, Folder 24)
    - "Morals, Religion, and Higher Education" (October 23, 1948) -- Slip Only, undated (Box 415, Folder 25)
    - "Morals, Religion, and Higher Education" (October 24, 1948), 1948 (Box 415, Folder 26)
    - "Morals, Religion, and Higher Education" (October 25, 1948), 1948 (Box 415, Folder 27)
    - "Higher Education Today" (October 29, 1948), 1948 (Box 415, Folder 28)
    - "A Business without a Balance Sheet" (November 4, 1948), 1948 (Box 415, Folder 29)
    - Burton-Judson Court (November 16, 1948), 1948 (Box 415, Folder 30)
    - National Conference of Editorial Writers (November 19, 1948), 1948 (Box 416, Folder 1)
    - "Education and Democracy" (December 12, 1948), 1948 (Box 416, Folder 2)
    - Trustees' Dinner (January 12, 1949), 1949 (Box 416, Folder 3)
    - Encyclopædia Britannica (January 17, 1949) -- Slip only, undated (Box 416, Folder 4)
    - "The College and the Needs of Society" (January 19, 1949), 1949 (Box 416, Folder 5)
    - New York Bar Association (January 26, 1949), 1949 (Box 416, Folder 6)
    - Southwestern at Memphis (February 8, 1949), 1948-1949 (Box 416, Folder 7)
    - "Business without a Balance Sheet" (February 8, 1949), 1949 (Box 416, Folder 8)
    - "Higher Education Today" (February 8, 1949), 1949 (Box 416, Folder 9)
    - Le Moyne College (February 8, 1949) -- Slip Only, undated (Box 416, Folder 10)
    - Student Union (February 22, 1949) -- Slip Only, undated (Box 416, Folder 11)
    - Charleston Open Forum (February 24, 1949), 1949 (Box 416, Folder 12)
    - "St. Thomas and the World State" (March 6, 1949), 1949 (Box 416, Folder 13)
    - "St. Thomas and the World State" (March 7, 1949) -- Slip Only, undated (Box 416, Folder 14)
    - "The College and the Needs of Society" (April 4, 1949), 1949 (Box 416, Folder 15)
    - "Higher Education Today" (April 6, 1949), 1949 (Box 416, Folder 16)
    - Great Books Foundation (April 16, 1949) -- Slip Only, undated (Box 416, Folder 17)
    - Inland Empire Association (April 6, 1949), 1949 (Box 417, Folder 1)
    - Inland Empire Association (April 6, 1949) -- Slip Only, undated (Box 417, Folder 2)
    - Great Books Foundation (April 8, 1949) -- Slip Only, undated (Box 417, Folder 3)
    - "On World Government "(April 11, 1949), 1949 (Box 417, Folder 4)
    - Illinois State Legislature (April 21, 1949), 1949 (Box 417, Folder 5)
    - "St. Thomas and the World State" (May 5, 1949) -- Slip Only, undated (Box 417, Folder 6)
    - "What Price Freedom?" (June 17, 1949), 1949 (Box 417, Folder 7)
    - American Friends Service Committee (June 21, 1949) -- Slip Only, undated (Box 417, Folder 8)
    - "What Price Freedom?" (June 22, 1949), 1949 (Box 417, Folder 9)
    - University of Chicago Law School (June 28, 1949), 1949 (Box 417, Folder 10)
    - Editors of Rural Education Journals (June 30, 1949), 1949 (Box 417, Folder 11)
    - "Goethe and the Unity of Mankind" (July 12, 1949), 1949 (Box 417, Folder 12)
    - "Adult Education – A Community Responsibility" (July 28, 1949), 1949 (Box 417, Folder 13)
    - "The Public Library: Its Place in Education" (August 8, 1949), 1949 (Box 417, Folder 14)
    - University of Chicago Entering Students (September 20, 1949), 1949 (Box 417, Folder 15)
    - Sonia Shankman Foundation (September 21, 1949), 1949 (Box 417, Folder 16)
    - "Morals, Religion, and Higher Education" (September 27, 1949), 1949 (Box 417, Folder 17)
    - Great Books Foundation (October 5, 1949), 1949 (Box 417, Folder 18)
    - "Morals, Religion, and Higher Education" (October 25, 1949), 1949 (Box 417, Folder 19)
    - "Americanism, Education, and Communism (November 14, 1949), 1949 (Box 417, Folder 20)
    - University of Chicago Settlement (November 21, 1949) -- Slip Only, undated (Box 417, Folder 21)
    - "Morals, Religion, and Higher Education" (November 29, 1949), 1949 (Box 417, Folder 22)
    - "Morals, Religion, and Higher Education" (December 6, 1949), 1949 (Box 417, Folder 23)
    - "The College and the Needs of Society" (December 9, 1949), 1949 (Box 417, Folder 24)
    - "Adult Education (December 9, 1949) -- Slip Only, undated (Box 418, Folder 1)
    - National Conference of Methodist Students (December 28, 1949) -- Slip Only, undated (Box 418, Folder 2)
    - Paul Russell's Funeral (January 10, 1950), 1950 (Box 418, Folder 3)
    - Trustee-Faculty Dinner (January 11, 1950), 1950 (Box 418, Folder 4)
    - University of Chicago Round Table (January 15, 1950), 1950 (Box 418, Folder 5)
    - "The College and the Needs of Society" (January 19, 1950), 1950 (Box 418, Folder 6)
    - Carnegie Corporation Dinner (January 24, 1950) -- Slip Only, undated (Box 418, Folder 7)
    - "Functions of the Modern University" (January 27, 1950), 1950 (Box 418, Folder 8)
    - "The Idea of a College" (February 18, 1950), 1950 (Box 418, Folder 9)
    - "World Government" (February 27, 1950), 1950 (Box 418, Folder 10)
    - Phelps Association Dinner (March 10, 1950) -- Slip Only, undated (Box 418, Folder 11)
    - "World Government" (March 12, 1950) -- Slip Only, undated (Box 418, Folder 12)
    - "The Idea of a College" (March 23, 1950), 1950 (Box 418, Folder 13)
    - "The Idea of a College" (March 25, 1950), 1950 (Box 418, Folder 14)
    - "The Idea of a College"/"The University as a Leader" (April 19, 1950), 1950 (Box 418, Folder 15)
    - Women's Inter-Dormitory Council (April 25, 1950) -- Slip Only, undated (Box 418, Folder 16)
    - "The University as a Leader" (April 28, 1950), 1950 (Box 418, Folder 17)
    - "American Education – Different from Any Other" (May 16, 1950), 1950 (Box 418, Folder 18)
    - "American Education" (May 17, 1950), 1950 (Box 418, Folder 19)
    - Goldblatt Cancer Hospital Dedication (June 15, 1950) -- Slip Only, undated (Box 418, Folder 20)
    - "The Inscription on Our Hearts" (June 16, 1950), 1950 (Box 418, Folder 21)
    - "The Inscription on Our Hearts" (June 21, 1950), 1950 (Box 418, Folder 22)
    - Basic Program Graduating Exercises (June 22, 1950), 1950 (Box 418, Folder 23)
    - "Education" (June 27, 1950), 1950 (Box 418, Folder 24)
    - "Freedom as a Moral Concept" (June 29, 1950), 1950 (Box 418, Folder 25)
    - University of Chicago Round Table (July 9, 1950), 1950 (Box 418, Folder 26)
    - University of Chicago Entering Students (September 27, 1950), 1950 (Box 419, Folder 1)
    - American Meat Institute (October 3, 1950), 1950 (Box 419, Folder 2)
    - "The Freedom of the University" (November 1, 1950), 1950 (Box 419, Folder 3)
    - Midwest Conference of Educators (November 3, 1950), 1950 (Box 419, Folder 4)
    - Roosevelt College Alumni (November 16, 1950) -- Slip Only, undated (Box 419, Folder 5)
    - "The Freedom of the University" (November 21, 1950), 1950 (Box 419, Folder 6)
    - "The Freedom of the University" (December 6, 1950), 1950 (Box 419, Folder 7)
    - Trustee- Faculty Dinner (January 10, 1951), 1951 (Box 419, Folder 8)
    - Farewell Address to University of Chicago Students (February 2, 1951), 1951 (Box 419, Folder 9)
    - Chicagoan of the Year Luncheon (February 5, 1951), 1951 (Box 419, Folder 10)
    - University of Chicago Law Review (February 5, 1951) -- Slip Only, undated (Box 419, Folder 11)
    - "The Outlook for Education" (February 11, 1951), 1951 (Box 419, Folder 12)
    - "Can We Preserve Freedom and Achieve Security?" (February 16, 1951), 1951 (Box 419, Folder 13)
    - "Education" (February 20, 1951), 1951 (Box 419, Folder 14)
    - Pasadena Civic Auditorium (April 24, 1951), 1951 (Box 419, Folder 15)
    - "Why Education has Failed" (May 2, 1951), 1951 (Box 419, Folder 16)
    - University of Chicago Alumni (June 9, 1951), 1951 (Box 419, Folder 17)
    - Southern Illinois University (June 10, 1951), 1951 (Box 419, Folder 18)
    - Brandeis University Convocation (June 17, 1951), 1951 (Box 419, Folder 19)
    - "Why Education has Failed" (July 19, 1951), 1951 (Box 419, Folder 20)
    - "The Conditions of Peace (July 26, 1951), 1951 (Box 420, Folder 1)
    - Aspen Institute (July 27, 1951), 1951 (Box 420, Folder 2)
    - Convocation – Free University of Berlin (August 6, 1951), 1951 (Box 420, Folder 3)
    - Gottesman Lectures – General (October 1-3, 1951), 1915-1952 (Box 420, Folder 4)
    - Gottesman Lectures – II (October 1, 1951), 1951 (Box 420, Folder 5)
    - Gottesman Lectures – III (October 2, 1951), 1951 (Box 420, Folder 6)
    - Gottesman Lectures – IV (October 3, 1951), 1951 (Box 420, Folder 7)
    - University of Chicago Inauguration Committee (October 18, 1951), 1951 (Box 420, Folder 8)
    - "Does Our Education Educate?" (October 24, 1951), 1951 (Box 420, Folder 9)
    - "The Conditions of Peace" (November 7, 1951), 1951 (Box 420, Folder 10)
    - "The Conditions of Peace" (November 20, 1951) -- Slip Only, undated (Box 420, Folder 11)
    - "The Conditions of Peace" (November 20, 1951), 1951 (Box 420, Folder 12)
    - Mirror – CBS TV Forum (December 25, 1951), 1951 (Box 420, Folder 13)
    - Los Angeles County Medical Association (January 15, 1952), 1952 (Box 420, Folder 14)
    - "Outlook for Education" (February 12, 1952), 1952 (Box 421, Folder 1)
    - "Education for Freedom" (February 20, 1952), 1951-1952 (Box 421, Folder 2)
    - "Some Questions about Education in North America" (March 4, 1952), 1952 (Box 421, Folder 3)
    - "Some Questions about Education in North America" - I (March 4, 1952), 1951-1953 (Box 421, Folder 4)
    - "Some Questions about Education in North America" – II (March 5, 1952), 1952 (Box 421, Folder 5)
    - Pasadena Chamber of Commerce (April 4, 1952), 1952 (Box 421, Folder 6)
    - Great Book of the Western World Dinner (April 15, 1952), 1952 (Box 421, Folder 7)
    - "Higher Education Today" (May 25, 1952), 1952 (Box 421, Folder 8)
    - Stetson University Commencement (June 2, 1952), 1952 (Box 421, Folder 9)
    - "The Democratic Dilemma" (September 10, 1952), 1952 (Box 421, Folder 10)
    - "Education on Trial" (October 14, 1952), 1952 (Box 421, Folder 11)
    - "Education on Trial" (October 14, 1952), 1952 (Box 421, Folder 12)
    - "Education on Trial" (October 23, 1952), 1952 (Box 421, Folder 13)
    - "The Independent College" (October 24, 1952), 1952 (Box 421, Folder 14)
    - "American Education" (October 30-31, 1952), 1951-1952 (Box 421, Folder 15)
    - "The Maxims of Democracy" (November 17, 1952), 1952 (Box 421, Folder 16)
    - American Civil Liberties Union (December 12, 1952), 1952 (Box 421, Folder 17)
    - "The Meaning of Education" (December 12, 1952), 1952-1953 (Box 422, Folder 1)
    - "The Meaning of Education" (February 6, 1953), 1952-1953 (Box 422, Folder 2)
    - "The Meaning of Education" (February 20, 1953), 1952-1953 (Box 422, Folder 3)
    - "The Meaning of Education" (March 8, 1953), 1953 (Box 422, Folder 4)
    - "Education in One World" (March 26, 1953), 1952-1953 (Box 422, Folder 5)
    - "Hazards to Education in the U.S. I: Industrialization" (April 6, 1953), 1952-1966 (Box 422, Folder 6)
    - "Hazards to Education in the U.S. II: Specialization" (April 7, 1953), 1953 (Box 422, Folder 7)
    - "Hazards to Education in the U.S. III: Philosophical Diversity" (April 8, 1953), 1953 (Box 422, Folder 8)
    - "Hazards to Education in the U.S. IV: Social and Political Conformity" (April 9, 1953), 1953 (Box 422, Folder 9)
    - Tulane University Commencement (June 2, 1953), 1953 (Box 422, Folder 10)
    - "The University of Utopia" (July 21, 1953), 1953 (Box 422, Folder 11)
    - "Human Relations" (September 15, 1953), 1953 (Box 422, Folder 12)
    - Brandeis University Alumni (October 7, 1953), 1953 (Box 422, Folder 13)
    - Brandeis University Alumni (October 11, 1953), 1953 (Box 422, Folder 14)
    - "Education and World Peace" (October 25, 1953), 1953 (Box 422, Folder 15)
    - "Education: Has it a Future?" (November 10, 1953), 1953 (Box 422, Folder 16)
    - Beloit College Symposium (November 12, 1953), 1953 (Box 423, Folder 1)
    - "The American Way of Life" (December 1, 1953), 1953 (Box 423, Folder 2)
    - "Education: Has it a Future?" (December 19, 1953), 1953 (Box 423, Folder 3)
    - "Education: Has it a Future?" (February 5, 1954), 1953-1954 (Box 423, Folder 4)
    - "Education: Has it a Future?" (February 21, 1954), 1953-1954 (Box 423, Folder 5)
    - Urban League of St. Louis (February 22, 1954), 1953-1954 (Box 423, Folder 6)
    - "Education: Has it a Future?" (February 23, 1954), 1954 (Box 423, Folder 7)
    - "Education: Has it a Future?" (February 26, 1954), 1954 (Box 423, Folder 8)
    - "Education: Has it a Future?" (February 28, 1954), 1953-1954 (Box 423, Folder 9)
    - "National Freedom" (March 19-20, 1954), 1954 (Box 423, Folder 10)
    - "What is a Community?" (March 25, 1954), 1954 (Box 423, Folder 11)
    - "Community" (April 2, 1954), 1954 (Box 423, Folder 12)
    - "Community" (April 26, 1954), 1954 (Box 423, Folder 13)
    - "Community" (April 28, 1954), 1954 (Box 423, Folder 14)
    - "Community" (May 11, 1954), 1954 (Box 423, Folder 15)
    - "Community" (May 12, 1954), 1954 (Box 423, Folder 16)
    - "The Meaning of America" (May 19, 1954), 1954 (Box 423, Folder 17)
    - "The United Nations" (May 26, 1954), 1954 (Box 423, Folder 18)
    - Haverford College Commencement (June 4, 1954), 1954 (Box 423, Folder 19)
    - "American Education" (Watson Lectures) (October 12-21, 1954), 1953-1954 (Box 423, Folder 20)
    - "The Meaning of Oberlin" (November 16, 1954), 1954 (Box 423, Folder 21)
    - "Education in America" (November 29, 1954), 1954 (Box 423, Folder 22)
    - Texas A. & M. College (December 5, 1954), 1954 (Box 423, Folder 23)
    - "The Thud of the Gate Receipts," undated (Box 423, Folder 24)
    - University of Texas (December 6, 1954), 1954 (Box 423, Folder 25)
    - "Breakstone Breaks Through" (January 10, 1955), 1955 (Box 423, Folder 26)
    - "Our Strength is in Our Freedom" (January 20, 1955), 1954-1955 (Box 423, Folder 27)
    - National Press Club (January 26, 1955), 1954-1955 (Box 424, Folder 1)
    - "Education for Today" (January 27, 1955), 1954-1955 (Box 424, Folder 2)
    - "The Aims of Education (March 17, 1955), 1954-1955 (Box 424, Folder 3)
    - "Academic Freedom" (April 2, 1955), 1955 (Box 424, Folder 4)
    - "The Sources of National Strength" (April 16, 1955), 1955 (Box 424, Folder 5)
    - "Challenging the American Press" (April 21, 1955), 1955 (Box 424, Folder 6)
    - "Liberal Education" (May 11, 1955), 1955 (Box 424, Folder 7)
    - "The Meaning of Oberlin" (May 17, 1955), 1955 (Box 424, Folder 8)
    - Asheville School Commencement (June 4, 1955), 1955 (Box 424, Folder 9)
    - Berea College Commencement (June 6, 1955), 1955 (Box 424, Folder 10)
    - "The Aims of Democracy" (June 29, 1955), 1955 (Box 424, Folder 11)
    - "Education and Accommodation" (August 9, 1955), 1955-1956 (Box 424, Folder 12)
    - "The Administrator Reconsidered" (September 19, 1955), 1955-1956 (Box 424, Folder 13)
    - "Education and the Mature Person" (September 26, 1955), 1955 (Box 424, Folder 14)
    - "The Fund for the Republic" (September 30, 1955), 1955 (Box 425, Folder 1)
    - American Veterans Committee (October 7, 1955), 1955 (Box 425, Folder 2)
    - "Civil Liberties and Education" (November 1, 1955), 1955 (Box 425, Folder 3)
    - "The Promise of Education" (November 18, 1955) [1 of 2], 1955 (Box 425, Folder 4)
    - "The Promise of Education" (November 18, 1955) [2 of 2], 1955 (Box 425, Folder 5)
    - "Civil Liberties and Civil Rights" (December 10, 1955), 1955 (Box 425, Folder 6)
    - American Civil Liberties Union (January 9, 1956), 1956 (Box 425, Folder 7)
    - "The Promise of Education" (January 11, 1956), 1955-1956 (Box 425, Folder 8)
    - "The Promise of Education" (January 16, 1956), 1955-1956 (Box 425, Folder 9)
    - "The Promise of Education" (January 17, 1956), 1955-1956, Reed College (January 17, 1956), 1956 (Box 425, Folder 10)
    - "The Promise of Education" (January 18, 1956), 1955-1956 (Box 425, Folder 11)
    - "The Promise of Education" (January 19, 1956), 1955-1956 (Box 425, Folder 12)
    - "The Place of Foundations in American Life" (January 20, 1956), 1956 (Box 425, Folder 13)
    - American Jewish Congress (January 31, 1956), 1955-1956 (Box 425, Folder 14)
    - Young Presidents' Organization (February 9, 1956), 1956 (Box 425, Folder 15)
    - "The Promise of Education" (February 13, 1956), 1955-1956 (Box 425, Folder 16)
    - "The Place of Foundations in American Life" (February 14, 1956), 1955-1956 (Box 425, Folder 17)
    - Discussions, Inc. (February 17, 1956), 1955-1956 (Box 425, Folder 18)
    - "The Bill of Rights Yesterday, Today, and Tomorrow" (February 18, 1956), 1956 (Box 425, Folder 19)
    - "Freedom of the University" (February 24, 1956), 1956 (Box 425, Folder 20)
    - "Freedom of the University" (March 6, 1956), 1956 (Box 425, Folder 21)
    - "On Civil Liberties" (March 25, 1956), 1956 (Box 425, Folder 22)
    - "The Future of Education" (April 12, 1956), 1956 (Box 426, Folder 1)
    - "On Civil Liberties – The Bill of Rights" (April 20, 1956), 1955-1956 (Box 426, Folder 2)
    - Basic Program of Liberal Education (June 11, 1956), 1956 (Box 426, Folder 3)
    - National Association of Cost Accountants (June 19, 1956), 1955-1956 (Box 426, Folder 4)
    - WRCA-TV (August 9, 1956), 1956 (Box 426, Folder 5)
    - Conference on Science and Human Responsibility (November 2, 1956), 1956-1961 (Box 426, Folder 6)
    - "Civil Liberties in an Age of Fear" (November 19, 1956), 1956 (Box 426, Folder 7)
    - "The State of Liberty" (November 25, 1956), 1956 (Box 426, Folder 8)
    - American Jewish Congress (December 3, 1956), 1956 (Box 426, Folder 9)
    - "Civil Liberties in an Age of Fear" (December 4, 1956), 1956 (Box 426, Folder 10)
    - "Civil Liberties in an Age of Anxiety" (December 11, 1956), 1956 (Box 426, Folder 11)
    - "Are Tax Exempt Foundations Serving the Public Interest?" (January 23, 1957), 1956-1957 (Box 426, Folder 12)
    - "Administering a Foundation in a Free Society" (January 29, 1957), 1956-1957 (Box 426, Folder 13)
    - Harvard Law School Forum (February 15, 1957), 1956-1957 (Box 426, Folder 14)
    - "The Education of the Present Generation" (March 2, 1957), 1956-1957 (Box 426, Folder 15)
    - "Education on Trial" (February 24, 1957), 1956-1957 (Box 426, Folder 16)
    - "The New Society" (Hillman Lectures) (March 11-13, 1957) [1 of 3], 1957 (Box 426, Folder 17)